<doc name="faq" title="FAQ">
<h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2>
<qatable>
<qa>
  <q>Can the DataPump be used to update SeviceNow from a SQL database?</q>
  <a>No. The DataPump only updates SQL from ServiceNow.</a>
</qa>
<qa>
  <q>Why not modify the DataPump so that it can move data in either direction?</q>
  <a>Updating ServiceNow from an SQL database is a completely different problem,
  and there are other, better solutions.
  The DataPump creates tables in the SQL database, so it knows
  that the column names will match and the primary key will always be 
  <name>sys_id</name>.
  If the starting point is SQL, it will be necessary to identify a field map
  and a key on which to coalesce.  The recommended solution is to use
  a ServiceNow Transform Map with a JDBC Data Source.
  </a>
</qa>
<qa>
  <q>What is the <name>-cancel</name> option and how does it work?</q>
  <a>If a <b>signal file</b> is defined in the
  <page name="configuration" sect="properties"/> file,
  then the DataPump will check for existence of this file after every SOAP call,
  or once per second while it is sleeping.  If the file is detected,
  the application will generate an internal <name>InterruptedException</name>.
  This provides a clean mechanism to shut down the application if it is 
  in the middle of long-running job set.  The <name>-cancel</name> 
  command link option simply creates the signal file and terminates,
  allowing for any other running instance of the application to detect
  that the file has been created.  
  </a>
</qa>
<qa>
  <q>If I add a field to a ServiceNow table, will the DataPump add this field
  to the SQL table next time it is run?</q>
  <a>No.  The DataPump only generates DDL if a table does not already exist
  in the target database.  If you add a field to a ServiceNow table,
  then you must manually add a field with the same name to the SQL table.
  Once the field has been added, the DataPump will update it.</a>
</qa>
<qa>
  <q>The DataPump seems to replicate all fields in the table.  What if I do not
  want all the fields to be replicated?</q>
  <a>Simply drop the field from the SQL table.  
  As part of its start-up process, the DataPump compares the field names
  between the source and the target tables.  It only replicates those
  fields where it finds a match.</a>
</qa>
</qatable>
</doc>