<doc name="gui" title="GUI">
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>GUI mode allows the application to be configured and monitored
using ServiceNow.
In order to use GUI mode you must install an Update Set in
your ServiceNow instance.
The Update Set creates three tables</p>
<ul>
<li>u_datapump_jobset</li>
<li>u_datapump_job</li>
<li>u_m2m_datapump_jobs</li>
</ul>
<p>Use the following command line option
to execute a Jobset which has been configured
in the ServiceNow instance.</p>
<syntax><more><kw>-js</kw><var>jobsetname</var></more></syntax>

<h2>Jobset</h2>
<p>This screenshot shows a Jobset with twelve jobs.
The Jobset is being used to load 2010 (historical) Incident data
one month at a time.</p>
<screenshot name="load"/>

<h2>Load Job</h2>
<p>A <b>Load</b> job may specify a date range and/or filter conditions.
In order to specify a date range, the <b>Interval Field</b>
must be set to "Created" or "Updated".
This screenshot shows a Load Job with conditions, but no date range.
</p>
<screenshot name="conditions"/>

<h2>Refresh Job</h2>
<p>A <b>Refresh</b> job will update/insert all records in the
target SQL database that have been updated or inserted
in ServiceNow since the job last ran.
Each time the job runs the <b>Interval Start</b>
and <b>Interval End</b> fields will be updated.
This screenshot shows a Refresh Job for the Incident table.
</p>
<screenshot name="refresh"/>

<h2>Prune Job</h2>
<p>A <b>Prune</b> job checks <code>sys_audit_delete</code>
for records which have been deleted in ServiceNow since it last run.
If it detects deleted records they will be deleted in the target database.
As with a Refresh Job, the Prune Job updates the 
<b>Interval Start</b> and <b>Interval End</b> each time it runs.
This Prune job checks for any Change Task records which have been deleted. 
</p>
<screenshot name="prune"/>

<h2>SQL Job</h2>
<p>A <b>SQL</b> job will execute an arbitrary SQL statement.  
These jobs can be used to transform the data after it 
has been loaded from the ServiceNow instance.</p>
<screenshot name="sql"/>

</doc>